#### **Kenneth Carroll**

# **Software Engineer**

Kenneth.James.Carroll@gmail.com | 606-706-2887 | KJCDevelopment.com

## **About Me**

I am a senior at Morehead State University pursuing a B.S. in a Space Science Area of Concentration. I am a self-educated Software Engineer with experience in low level C/C++ programming, Test Driven Development, along with Full Stack Web Development being my primary hobby.

### **Educational History**

- Madison Central High School Graduated May 2015 3.76 GPA
- Morehead State University Graduating May 2019 3.488 GPA

# **Relevant Work History**

- NASA Marshall Space Flight Center: Flight Software Testing and Verification Intern (June 2018-August 2018)
  - Update, modify, and document Design Level Requirement tests in C++ along with corresponding documentation

# **Relevant Volunteer History**

- Morehead State University Space Science Center: Dependable Multiprocessor Software Lead (May 2018-Current)
  - Integrate OpenClovis into existing Dependable Multiprocessor software and hardware received from Honeywell
- Morehead State University Space Science Center: DM Project Volunteer (November 2017-May 2018)

- Compile custom Linux images for Raspberry Pi devices for commercial Dependable Multiprocessor concept demonstration
- Morehead State University Space Science Center: Lunar IceCube Satellite Flight Software Team (August 2017-Current)
  - Write code modules for the flight software of Lunar IceCube Satellite using Core Flight Systems (cFS) along with constructing unit tests in C.
- Twiggs Space Lab: Volunteer Programmer (November 2017-Febuary 2018)
  - Assist in finding alternatives to XinaBox chips for ThinSat school education program. Program demonstrations to show Arduino based alternatives for ThinSat.

# **Technical Skills**

- Microcontroller Programming
- C/C++
- HTML & CSS
- Javascript
  - JQuery
  - NodeJS
  - o Express
- Python
- Bash Scripting
  - Testing Automation
  - o Environment Setup Automation
  - Kernel Virtual Machine Automation
- Linux/Unix Terminal
- Version Control (Git, SVN)
- Unit Testing & Regression Testing
- Technical Documentation Writing